Real heroes. Not actual size.
Ant-Man and the Wasp is a action, adventure, science
fiction film directed by Peyton Reed.
Just when his time under house arrest is about to end, Scott Lang once
again puts his freedom at risk to help Hope van Dyne and Dr.
Hank Pym dive into the quantum realm and try to accomplish, against time
and any chance of success, a very dangerous rescue mission.
Scott Lang / Ant-Man, played by Paul Rudd.
Hope Van Dyne / Wasp, played by Evangeline Lilly.
Dr. Hank Pym, played by Michael Douglas.
Ava / Ghost, played by Hannah John-Kamen.
Jimmy Woo, played by Randall Park.
Janet Van Dyne / Wasp, played by Michelle Pfeiffer.
Ant-Man and the Wasp is a 2018 American superhero film based on Marvel Comics
featuring the characters Scott Lang / Ant-Man and Hope Pym / Wasp.
Produced by Marvel Studios and distributed by Walt Disney Studios Motion Pictures, it is the
sequel to Ant-Man (2015) and the 20th film in the Marvel Cinematic Universe (MCU).
The film was directed by Peyton Reed and written by the writing teams of Chris McKenna
and Erik Sommers, and Paul Rudd, Andrew Barrer and Gabriel Ferrari.
It stars Rudd as Lang and Evangeline Lilly as Hope van Dyne, alongside Michael Peña, Walton Goggins, Hannah John-Kamen, David Dastmalchian, Tip
"T.I." Harris, Judy Greer, Bobby Cannavale, Randall Park, Abby Ryder Fortson, Michelle Pfeiffer, Laurence Fishburne, and Michael Douglas.
In the film, the titular pair work with Hank Pym (Douglas) to
retrieve Janet van Dyne (Pfeiffer) from the Quantum Realm.
Talks for a sequel to Ant-Man began shortly after that film was released.
Ant-Man and the Wasp was officially announced in October 2015, with
Rudd and Lilly returning to reprise their roles.
A month later, Ant-Man director Reed was officially set to return.
He had joined the first film later in its production and was
excited to develop this one from the beginning.
He also looked forward to introducing Hope van Dyne as the Wasp in this
film, and insisted on treating Lang and her as equals.
Filming took place from August to November 2017, at Pinewood Atlanta Studios in Fayette County,
Georgia, as well as Metro Atlanta; San Francisco; Savannah, Georgia; and Hawaii.
Ant-Man and the Wasp had its world premiere in Hollywood, Los Angeles, on June 25, 2018, and was
released in the United States on July 6, 2018, as part of Phase Three of the MCU.
The film was a critical and commercial success, receiving praise for its performances (particularly
those of Rudd and Lilly), humor, and levity, and grossing over $622 million worldwide.
A sequel, Ant-Man and the Wasp: Quantumania, was released in February 2023.
The film explores themes of van, dreams, insect, flying, chase.
The tone is thought_provoking.